Guide to the Western Filmscript Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Western filmscript collection
1918-2013
WA MSS S-1610
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
157.60
(190 boxes)
The Western Filmscript Collection consists of over two thousand filmscripts dating from 1918 to 2008, for motion pictures set in the trans-Mississippi West. The collection includes continuity, cutting, dialogue, and shooting scripts in a range of drafts from initial to final, and in some cases revised versions of the same draft. Scripts for produced, as well as unproduced, films are represented. Highlights include: fifteen Tom Mix silent scenarios from 1919 through 1927; four scripts by Zane Grey, including Riders of the Purple Sage (1931); eleven scripts directed by John Ford, including My Darling Clementine (1946), Stagecoach (1938), and Fort Apache (1947); five films featuring Gary Cooper, including The Virginian (1929), High Noon (1952), and Springfield Rifle (1952); eleven featuring Clint Eastwood, including For a Few Dollars More (1966), Dirty Harry (1970), and Pale Rider (1985). Scripts set in the twentieth-century West include American Graffiti (1972), Beverly Hills Cop (1984), The Buddy Holly Story (1978), Heaven's Gate (1979), The Long Goodbye (1972), and Terms of Endearment (1981). In addition to scripts written for theatrical release, there are scripts for episodes of television series including Rawhide, Death Valley Days, Dallas, and others.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from various sources since 1982.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Other Finding Aids
The Western Filmscript Collection Database provides the ability to employ boolean search operators across fields of data to isolate relevant scripts.
Scope and Contents
The Western Filmscript Collection consists of over two thousand filmscripts dating from 1918 to 2008, for motion pictures set in the trans-Mississippi West. The collection includes continuity, cutting, dialogue, and shooting scripts in a range of drafts from initial to final, and in some cases revised versions of the same draft. Photographs accompany a small number of scripts. Scripts for produced, as well as unproduced films, are represented. Highlights include: fifteen Tom Mix silent scenarios from 1919 through 1927; four scripts by Zane Grey, including Riders of the Purple Sage (1931); eleven scripts directed by John Ford, including My Darling Clementine (1946), Stagecoach (1938), and Fort Apache (1947); five films featuring Gary Cooper, including The Virginian (1929), High Noon (1952), and Springfield Rifle (1952); eleven featuring Clint Eastwood, including For a Few Dollars More (1966), Dirty Harry (1970), and Pale Rider (1985). Scripts set in the twentieth-century West include American Graffiti (1972), Beverly Hills Cop (1984), The Buddy Holly Story (1978), Heaven's Gate (1979), The Long Goodbye (1972), and Terms of Endearment (1981).In addition to scripts written for theatrical release, there are teleplays for episodes of television series including Rawhide, Death Valley Days, Dallas, and others.
Arrangement
Organized into two groups: Western Filmscripts Acquired Before July 1996, and Western Filmscripts Acquired After July 1996.
Motion picture plays -- United States; Western films; West (U.S.) -- In motion pictures; West (U.S.) -- In popular culture; Screenplays; Television scripts
- Western Filmscripts Acquired Before July 1996, 1918-1989
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by title, with dates of scripts provided when available. The listing includes name of screenwriter as well as additional credits and notes.
  - Alvarez Kelly, July 19, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Story: Franklin Coen
    Screenplay: Franklin Coen Elliott Arnold
    Director: [Edward Dmytryk]
    Producer: [Sol C. Siegel]
    Actors: [William Holden Richard Widmark Paul Lukather]
    Production company: Ray David Productions
    Distributor: Columbia Pictures
    Setting: Cattle trail, 1864
    Type: Shooting
    Notes: Changes attached at beginning. "Paul Lukather" written on cover. "Webster" parts circled.
  - Alvarez Kelly, April 2, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Story: [Franklin Coen]
    Actors: [William Holden Richard Widmark Janice Rule]
    Type: Second estimating draft
    Notes: Working title: The Richmond Story
  - American Graffiti, May 10, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Screenplay: George Lucas Willard Huyck Gloria Katz
    Director: [George Lucas]
    Producer: [Francis Ford Coppola Gary Kurtz]
    Actors: [Richard Dreyfuss Ronny Howard Cindy Williams]
    Production company: Universal Pictures
    Distributor: Universal Pictures
    Setting: California, 1962
    Type: Second draft
    Notes: in library binding; withdrawn from Emerson College
  - Angel and the Badman, March 19, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Screenplay: James Edward Grant
    Director: James Edward Grant
    Producer: John Wayne
    Actors: John Wayne Gail Russell Harry Carey
    Production company: Republic Productions
    Distributor: Republic Productions
    Type: Shooting script
    Notes: Working title: The Gun
  - Apache Kid, July 18, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Screenplay: [Eliot Gibbons Richard Murphy]
    Director: [George Sherman]
    Producer: George Sherman (assoc)
    Actors: [Don Barry Lynn Merrick LeRoy Mason]
    Production company: Republic
    Distributor: Republic
    Setting: Oregon trail
  - Apache Territory, October 17, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Story: [Louis L'Amour]
    Screenplay: [Charles R. Mason] [George W. George]
    Director: Ray Nazarro
    Producer: Rory Calhoun Victor Orsatti
    Actors: Rory Calhoun [Barbara Bates John Dehner]
    Production company: Calhoun-Orsatti Enterprises, Inc. (Rorvic)
    Setting: 1880, Apache Territory
    Type: Final draft
    Notes: Working title: Papago Wells
  - Apache Trail, August 23, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Story: [Ernest Haycox]
    Screenplay: [Maurice Geraghty]
    Director: [Richard Thorpe]
    Producer: [Samuel Marx]
    Actors: [Lloyd Nolan Donna Reed William Lundigan]
    Production company: Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer
    Distributor: Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer
    Setting: New Mexico
    Type: Temporary complete
    Notes: Working title: Desert Station
  - Apache Uprising, December 2, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Story: Harry Sanford Max Steeber
    Screenplay: Harry Sanford Max Lamb
    Director: R. G. Springsteen
    Producer: A. C. Lyles
    Actors: Rory Calhoun Corinne Calvet Lon Chaney
    Production company: Paramount Pictures
    Distributor: Paramount Pictures
    Type: Release dialogue
  - The Appaloosa, September 30, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Story: Robert MacLeod
    Screenplay: James Bridges [Roland Kibbee]
    Director: Sidney J. Furie
    Producer: [Alan Miller]
    Actors: Marlon Brando Anjanette Comer John Saxon
    Production company: Universal City Studios
    Distributor: Universal City Studios
    Setting: Mexico, turn of the century
    Notes: On cover, "David L. Watson - Wardrobe" Wardrobe copy with handwritten annotations, photos of costumes pasted in, the shooting schedule, etc. Working titles: Cocatlan; Southwest
  - Arabia, 1922 release (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Story: Lynn Reynolds
    Screenplay: Lynn Reynolds Tom Mix
    Director: Lynn Reynolds
    Actors: Tom Mix [Barbara Bedford George Hernandez]
    Production company: William Fox Vaudeville Co.
    Setting: Arabia
    Notes: Working title: An Arabian Knight
  - The Arizona Kid, February 3, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Story: [O. Henry]
    Screenplay: Ralph Block Peggy Lent Helen Barnhart [Joseph Wright]
    Director: Alfred Santell
    Actors: Warner Baxter Mona Maris Theodore Von Eltz
    Distributor: [Fox]
    Setting: Arizona, 1889-93
    Type: Second continuity
  - The Arizona Wildcat, January 14,1926 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Screenplay: Adela Rogers St. Johns (John Stone)
    Director: R. William Neill
    Actors: Tom Mix Dorothy Sebastian Gordon Elliot
    Type: Plot synopsis
    Notes: Working title: High Society
  - Arrowhead (Subtitle: Adobe Walls), September 5, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Screenplay: Charles Marquis Warren
    Director: Charles Marquis Warren
    Producer: Nat Holt
    Actors: Charlton Heston Jack Palance Katy Jurado
    Type: Final white
    Notes: on front cover, "Corporal Ives - Mike Ragan"
  - Bad Company, December 1970 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Screenplay: David Newman Robert Benton
    Director: Robert Benton
    Producer: Stanley Jaffe
    Actors: Jeff Bridges Barry Brown
    Production company: Alpha-60, Renn Productions
    Setting: On trail West
  - Bad Girls, August 17, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Story: Yolande Finch
    Screenplay: Ken Friedman
    Director: Jonathan Kaplan
    Producer: Lynda Obst (exec)
    Actors: [Mary Stuart Masterson Andy MacDowell Drew Barrymore Madeleine Stowe]
    Notes: "Neil Summers" written on cover
  - The Badlanders, November 14, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Story: [W. R. Burnett]
    Screenplay: Richard Collins
    Director: [Delmer Daves]
    Producer: Aaron Rosenberg
    Actors: [Alan Ladd Ernest Borgnine Katy Jurado]
    Production company: Arcola Pictures
  - The Ballad of Cable Hogue, October 24, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Story: John Crawford Edmond Penney
    Screenplay: John Crawford Edmund Penny Gordon Dawson
    Director: [Sam Peckinpah]
    Producer: [Sam Peckinpah]
    Actors: Jason Robards David Warner Stella Stevens
    Production company: Warner Brothers
    Distributor: Warner Brothers
    Setting: Desert
    Type: Final
    Notes: Incomplete copy.
  - The Ballad of Cable Hogue, September 4, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Screenplay: [John Crawford] [Edmund Penny]
    Actors: [Jason Robards Stella Stevens David Warner]
    Production company: Phil Feldman Productions
    Distributor: Warner Brothers - Seven Arts, Inc.
    Type: Estimating script
    Notes: "Malcolm Beelby" written on front cover
  - The Ballad of Dingus Magee, September 28, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Story: [David Markson]
    Screenplay: Tim Waldman Frank Waldman [Joseph Heller]
    Director: [Burt Kennedy]
    Producer: Lawrence Weingarten [Burt Kennedy]
    Actors: [Frank Sinatra George Kennedy Anne Jackson]
    Production company: Marten Productions
    Setting: Southwest
    Type: Draft
    Notes: Marked "H. Krebs." Working title: Dirty Dingus Magee
  - Barbed Wire, May 24, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Screenplay: John D. F. Black
    Producer: Howard Christie
    Setting: Kansas City
    Notes: "Nagene Searle" label on cover. Working title: Gannon
  - Belle of the Yukon, March 11, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Story: [Houston Branch]
    Director: William A. Seiter
    Producer: [William A. Seiter]
    Actors: [Randolph Scott Gypsy Rose Lee Dinah Shore]
    Production company: International Pictures, Inc.
    Distributor: RKO Radio Pictures
    Setting: the Yukon, Gold Rush
    Type: Final - complete
  - Belle Starr, November 16, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    Story: [Niven Busch Cameron Rogers]
    Screenplay: Lamar Trotti
    Director: [Irvin Cummings]
    Producer: [Kenneth MacGowan (assoc)]
    Actors: [Randolph Scott Gene Tierney Dana Andrews]
    Production company: [Twentieth Century- Fox]
    Distributor: [Twentieth Century-Fox]
    Setting: 1865, Missouri
    Type: Temporary draft
  - Belle Starr, February 12, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Type: Revised Final
  - Belle Starr, March 13, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    Type: Final Draft
    Notes: Additional margin notes.
  - Belle Starr, March 4, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    Screenplay: James Lee Barrett
    Director: John A. Alonzo
    Actors: Elizabeth Montgomery Cliff Potts Michael Cavanaugh
    Production company: Hanna-Barbera
    Distributor: CBS-TV
    Type: First draft
    Notes: aired in 1980
  - The Bells of Rosarita, 1945 release (Box 4, Folder 26)
    Screenplay: Jack Townley
    Director: Frank McDonald
    Producer: Eddy White (assoc)
    Actors: Roy Rogers George Hayes Dale Evans
    Production company: Republic Pictures
    Distributor: Republic Pictures
    Setting: 1930, California
    Type: Cutting continuity
  - The Bells of Rosarita, December 1, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    Director: [Frank McDonald]
    Actors: [Roy Rogers George Hayes Dale Evans]
  - Beneath Western Skies, November 18, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    Story: [Albert DeMond]
    Screenplay: Albert DeMond Bob Williams
    Director: Spencer Gordon Bennett
    Producer: Louis Gray (assoc)
    Actors: [Robert Livingston Smiley Burnette Effie Laird]
    Setting: Stokesville
    Notes: "John Paul Revere" series.
  - Beverly Hills Cop, February 20, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    Story: [Daniel Petrie, Jr. Danilo Bach]
    Screenplay: Daniel Petrie, Jr.
    Director: [Martin Brest]
    Producer: Don Simpson Jerry Bruckheimer
    Actors: [Eddie Murphy Judge Reinhold Lisa Eilbacher]
    Setting: Beverly Hills, 1980s
    Type: Third draft
    Notes: In library binding, withdrawn from Emerson College.
  - Beyond the Purple Hills, August 10, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    Screenplay: Gerald Geraghty [Norman S. Hall]
    Director: John English
    Producer: Armand Schaefer
    Actors: Pat Buttram Jo Dennison Gene Autry
    Production company: Columbia Pictures
    Notes: handwritten date on cover "November 7, 1949"
  - A Big Hand for the Little Lady (Subtitle: A Big Deal at Dodge City), May 21, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    Screenplay: Sidney Carroll
    Director: [Fielder Cook]
    Producer: [Fielder Cook]
    Actors: [Henry Fonda Joanne Woodward Jason Robards]
    Production company: Eden Productions
    Setting: The West, 1896
    Notes: Annotated throughout. Working title: A Big Deal at Dodge City.
  - Billy Jack, May 12, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    Screenplay: Frank Christina Teresa Christina
    Director: T. C. Frank (Delores Taylor)
    Producer: Mary Rose Solti
    Actors: Tom Laughlin Delores Taylor Clark Howat
    Production company: National Student Film Corp.
    Type: Script basis for foreign subtitles
  - Billy the Kid, Wanted, 1941 release (Box 5, Folder 33)
    Screenplay: Fred Myton
    Director: [Sam Newfield (Sherman Scott)]
    Producer: [Sigmund Neufeld]
    Actors: Al St. John Dave O'Brien Buster Crabbe
    Production company: Producers Releasing Corporation
    Distributor: Producers Releasing Corporation
    Notes: Billy the Kid series
  - Billy Two Hats, August 15, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    Screenplay: Alan Sharp
    Director: [Ted Kotcheff]
    Producer: [Norman Jewison Patrick Palmer]
    Actors: Gregory Peck Desi Arnaz, Jr. [Jack Warden]
    Production company: Algonquin Films, Ltd.
    Distributor: [United Artists]
    Setting: Arizona
    Notes: Working title: The Lady and the Outlaw
  - Blazing Saddles, December 21, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    Story: Andrew Bergman
    Screenplay: Mel Brooks Richard Pryor Andrew Bergman Norman Steinberg Alan Uger
    Director: Mel Brooks
    Producer: Michael Hertzberg
    Actors: Cleavon Little Slim Pickens Gene Wilder
    Type: Revised draft
    Notes: Working title: Black Bart
  - Blazing Saddles, November 3, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Blood on the Arrow, 1964 release (Box 6, Folder 37)
    Story: Mark Hanna
    Screenplay: Mark Hanna [Robert E. Kent]
    Director: Sidney Salkow
    Producer: [Leon Fromkess]
    Actors: Dale Robertson Martha Hyer Wendell Corey
    Production company: Allied Artists
    Distributor: Allied Artists
    Notes: "Mitchell Gertz Agency" stamp on front cover, title page
  - Blood on the Moon, November 15, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    Screenplay: Harold Shumate Luke Short Lillie Hayward
    Director: Robert Wise
    Producer: Theron Warth [Sid Rogell]
    Actors: Robert Mitchum Barbara Bel Geddes Robert Preston
    Production company: RKO Pictures
    Distributor: RKO Pictures
    Setting: Texas
    Type: English Master Titles
    Notes: Broken into reels and frames.
  - Boom Town Bad Men (Box 6, Folder 39)
    Screenplay: Ronald Davidson
    Actors: Ronald Davidson
    Production company: Monogram Productions
    Distributor: Monogram Productions
    Setting: Rough country
  - The Border, April 11, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    Screenplay: Deric Washburn Walon Green David Freeman
    Director: [Tony Richardson]
    Producer: Neil Hartley Edgar Bronfman, Jr.
    Actors: [Jack Nicholson Valerie Perrine Harvey Keitel]
    Production company: Universal Studios
    Distributor: Universal Studios
    Setting: Texas-Mexican Border, 1980's
  - The Border, August 7, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    Type: Revised final draft
  - The Border, January 28, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    Screenplay: Deric Washburn Walon Green [David Freeman]
    Type: Second revised final draft
    Notes: With revisions.
  - Border Incident, November 21, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    Story: George Zuckerman [John C. Higgins]
    Screenplay: John C. Higgins
    Director: Anthony Mann
    Producer: Nicholas Nayfack
    Actors: Ricardo Montalban George Murphy Howard Da Silva
    Setting: Imperial Valley, California
    Type: Dubbing, American instruction list
  - The Border Legion, March 5, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    Story: Zane Grey
    Screenplay: Percy Heath [Edward E. Paramore, Jr.]
    Director: Otto Brower Edwin H. Knopf
    Producer: Louis D. Lighton
    Actors: Richard Arlen Fay Wray Jack Holt
    Production company: Paramount Studio
    Distributor: Paramount Studio
    Setting: Utah, general West
    Notes: Broken into sequences A-G and then into scenes.
  - Borderland, November 12, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    Story: Clarence E. Mulford
    Screenplay: Harrison Jacobs
    Director: Nate Watt
    Producer: Harry Sherman
    Actors: Bill Boyd Jimmy Ellison George Hayes
    Setting: Mexican Border
    Notes: Hopalong Cassidy Series. Working title: Bring Me His Ears.
  - Bordertown Trail, April 21, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    Screenplay: [Bob Williams Jesse Duffy]
    Director: [Lesley Selander]
    Actors: [Smiley Burnette Sunset Carson Ellen Lowe]
    Setting: Texas after annexation
  - Boss of Boom Town, April 8, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    Screenplay: William Lively
    Director: Ray Taylor
    Producer: Oliver Drake
    Actors: Rod Cameron Tom Tyler Vivian Austin
    Notes: handwritten on front cover "Vivian Austin - Universal". "At-a- Glance" enclosed, dated April 27, 1944.
  - Boss of Rawhide, [November 20, 1943] (Box 7, Folder 48)
    Screenplay: Elmer Clifton
    Director: Elmer Clifton
    Producer: [Alfred Stern]
    Actors: [Dave O'Brien Jim Newill Guy Wilkerson]
    Production company: Stern Productions
    Setting: Rawhide, cattle country
    Notes: Texas Rangers Series.
  - Bounty Killer, [July 31, 1965] (Box 7, Folder 49)
    Screenplay: Leo Gordon [R. Alexander]
    Director: [Spencer Gordon Bennett]
    Producer: [Alex Gordon]
    Actors: [Dan Duryea Rod Cameron Audrey Dalton]
    Production company: Arwin Productions
    Distributor: Embassy
    Setting: 1868, Silver Creek, Colorado
  - Broken Arrow, June 11, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 50)
    Screenplay: Michael Blankfort
    Director: Delmer Daves
    Producer: Julian Blaustein
    Actors: James Stewart Jeff Chandler Debra Paget
    Production company: Twentieth Century-Fox
    Distributor: Twentieth Century-Fox
    Setting: Arizona, 1870
    Type: Revised final
    Notes: Handwritten on cover "prop & min". Working title: Arrow
  - Broken Arrow, May 20, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 51)
    Story: Elliot Arnold
    Notes: Handwritten on cover "prop & min". Working title: Arrow.
  - Broken Arrow, October 21, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 52)
    Producer: [Julian Blaustein]
    Actors: [James Stewart Jeff Chandler Debra Paget]
    Notes: Working title: Arrow.
  - Broken Lance, January 27, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 53)
    Story: [Philip Yordan]
    Screenplay: [Richard Murphy]
    Actors: Spencer Tracy Richard Widmark Jean Peters
    Setting: 1880
    Notes: Revisions from February, 1954.
  - Broken Lance, December 21, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 54)
    Screenplay: Richard Murphy
    Actors: [Spencer Tracy Richard Widmark Jean Peters]
    Type: Writer's working script
  - Broken Lance, October 9, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 55)
    Type: First draft continuity
  - The Broncho Twister, December 10, 1926 (Box 8, Folder 56)
    Story: Adela Rogers St. Johns (John Stone)
    Director: Orville Dull
    Producer: Orville Dull
    Actors: Tom Mix Helen Costello George Irving
    Type: Second version and changes
  - Bronco Billy, July 17, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 57)
    Screenplay: Dennis E. Hackin
    Director: [Clint Eastwood]
    Actors: [Clint Eastwood Sondra Locke Geoffrey Lewis]
    Production company: Second Street Films
    Setting: Twentieth Century
  - Bronco Billy, August 31, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - Brothers in the Saddle, May 20, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 59)
    Screenplay: Norman Houston
    Producer: [Herman Schlom]
    Actors: Tim Holt Richard Martin Virginia Cox
    Production company: RKO Radio Pictures
    Setting: Southern Arizona, 1888
    Type: Final script
  - Buck and the Preacher, November 23, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 60)
    Story: [Ernest Kinoy Drake Walker]
    Screenplay: Ernest Kinoy
    Director: Sidney Poitier
    Producer: [Joel Glickman]
    Actors: [Sidney Poitier Harry Belafonte Ruby Dee]
    Production company: E & R Productions / Belafonte Enterprises
  - The Buckskin Lady, 1957 release (Box 9, Folder 61)
    Story: [Francis S. Chase, Jr.]
    Screenplay: Carl K. Hittleman [David Lang]
    Director: Carl K. Hittleman
    Producer: [Carl K. Hittleman] D. Jersey Grut
    Actors: Patricia Medina Richard Denning Gerald Mohr
    Production company: Bishop-Hittleman Pictures
    Distributor: United Artists
    Setting: Nevada Territory, 1878
    Notes: handwritten on cover, "UA '57 SP David Lang, Carl Hittleman"
  - Bullet for a Bad Man (Subtitle: Renegade Posse), September 25, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 62)
    Story: [Marvin A. Albert]
    Screenplay: Mary Willingham Willard Willingham
    Producer: [Gordon Kay]
    Actors: Audie Murphy Darren McGavin Ruta Lee
    Production company: Universal International Pictures
    Distributor: Universal International Pictures
    Notes: Working title: Renegade Posse
  - Bullets and Saddles, 1943 release (Box 9, Folder 63)
    Story: Arthur Hoerl
    Screenplay: Elizabeth Beecher
    Director: Anthony Marshall
    Producer: George W. Weeks
    Actors: Ray Corrigan Dennis Moore Julie Duncan
    Distributor: [Monogram]
    Notes: handwritten on first page "Crash Corrigan"
  - Butch and Sundance (Subtitle: The Early Years), January 30, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 64)
    Screenplay: Allan Burns
    Director: [Richard Lester]
    Producer: [Gabriel Katzka Steven Bach]
    Actors: [Tom Berenger William Katt Jeff Corey]
    Setting: Utah, Nevada
    Notes: Working title: The Early Days
  - Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid, July 15, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 65)
    Screenplay: William Goldman
    Director: [George Roy Hill]
    Producer: [John Foreman]
    Actors: [Paul Newman Robert Redford Katharine Ross]
    Setting: 1880's
  - The Cactus Kid, November 6, 1930; October 28, 1930 (Box 10, Folder 66)
    Screenplay: James A. Starr Ebba Havez
    Setting: Montana
    Type: Second temporary; first temporary
    Notes: two versions bound together
  - Cannery Row, April 22, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 67)
    Story: John Steinbeck
    Screenplay: David S. Ward
    Director: David S. Ward
    Producer: Michael Phillips
    Actors: [Nick Nolte Debra Winger Audra Lindley]
    Setting: Monterey, CA
  - Chinatown, September 7, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 68)
    Screenplay: Robert Towne
    Director: Roman Polanski
    Producer: Robert Evans
    Actors: [Jack Nicholson Faye Dunaway John Huston]
    Production company: [Paramount Pictures]
    Distributor: [Paramount Pictures]
    Setting: Chinatown, San Francisco, 1930's
    Notes: "Linda Matheson" written on cover.
  - Chisum, 1970 release (Box 10, Folder 69)
    Screenplay: [Andrew V. McLaglen] Calvin Clements
    Director: [Andrew V. McLaglen]